Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network
World Bank Group Archives
- Management and oversight, 1998 - 2003; WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-07; 5.22 linear feet of textual records
  - Ian Johnson Meeting with Peter Woicke - Carbon Financing in World Bank Group - August 21, 2002 - Background Documentation, 2002-08-20 - 2002-10-18; 01833450
  - Consultation with Masafumi Kuroki, Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs - April 22, 2002 - Background Documentation, 2002-04-17 - 2002-04-22; 01833524
  - Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meetings with World Bank Managing Director, Shengman Zhang - General Correspondence - 2000, 2000-01-31 - 2000-12-21; 01833525
  - Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meeting with Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] TAC Chair, Emil Javier and CBC Chair, Kurt Peters - General Correspondence - July 21, 2000, 2000-05-23 - 2000-07-21; 01833527
  - Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meetings with World Bank Managing Director, Shengman Zhang - General Correspondence - 2001, 2001-02-22 - 2001-04-25; 01833528
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Retreat - Correspondence - March 26, 2002, 2002-03-26; 01833536
  - Organization and Management Records - Management Committee Meeting - Correspondence File - October 22, 2001, 2001-10-22; 01833537
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Retreat - Background Documentation - December 17, 2001, 2001-12-17; 01833538
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - 2000, 1999-12-15 - 2000-10-17; 01833539
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - 2001, 2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01833540
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - January 27, 2003, 2003-01-27; 01833542
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council - Background Documentation - 2000 - 2001, 2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01833543
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Retreat - Background Documentation - September 18, 2002, 2002-09-18; 01833544
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Meeting - Background Documentation - April 23, 2002, 2002-04-23; 01833545
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Meeting on Strategic Staffing - Correspondence File - January 15, 2003, 2003-01-15; 01833546
  - Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 1998, 1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31; 01833758
  - Organization and Management Records - Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - January 13 - 14, 2000, 2000-01-13 - 2000-01-14; 01833759
  - Organization and Management Records - Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - January 24 - 26, 2001, 2001-01-24 - 2001-01-26; 01833760
  - Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 1999, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01833761
  - Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 2000, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01833762
  - Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - September 13, 2002, 2002-09-13; 01833764
  - Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 1999 - Correspondence Records, 1999-08-18 - 1999-12-02; 01833771
  - Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 1999 and 2000 - Correspondence Records, 1999-10-19 - 2000-12-18; 01833772
  - Organization and Management Records - ESSD Knowledge Management Meeting - Correspondence File, 2002-08-22; 30181564
  - Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 2001, 2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01833763
  - Organization and Management Records - Strategic Compact and Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - December 2000 - January 2001, 2000-12-01 - 2001-01-31; 01833765
  - Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 2001 - Correspondence Records, 2001-01-03 - 2001-05-22; 01833773
  - Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 2002 - Correspondence Records, 2002-01-07 - 2002-07-15; 01833774
- ESSD Vice President's conference attendance and participation, 1998 - 2003; WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-03; 3.32 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of records related to ESSD Vice President Ian Johnson's attendance and participation at various conferences, seminars, and workshops organized by governments, agencies, and institutions external to the Bank. Records include: correspondence; briefing notes; agendas; list of participants; presentation notes; background papers and speeches written by Johnson or by other attendees; pamphlets; travel itineraries; and speakers' biographies.
  - Conferences and Seminars - University of Toronto World Bank Development Workshop - October 26 - 28, 1998 - General Correspondence, 1998-09-18 - 1998-10-21; 01832588
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Commission on Dams - Correspondence File, 2000-10-11 - 2001-03-20; 01832435
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Food Prize International Symposium - Des Moines - October 18, 2001 - Conference File, 2001-10-18; 01832517
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Johannesburg - August 26 - September 4, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-08-26 - 2002-09-04; 01832438
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Outcomes and Follow Up - August 26 - December 4, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-08-26 - 2002-12-04; 01832443
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Preparations for World Bank Participation - August 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-08-01 - 2002-08-31; 01832445
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Water Forum III - Kyoto - November 25, 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-11-12 - 2003-01-30; 01832419
  - Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcom II - New York - January 31, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-01-31; 01832446
  - Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcom II Meeting - Ian Johnson's Briefing to the Board on World Bank Participation - February 6, 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-02-06; 01832436
  - Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcomm and GEF Energy Roundtable - New York - January 28 - February 1, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-01-28 - 2002-02-01; 01832439
  - Correspondence File - Forestry Briefing - Reference Code Meeting Treatment of Revised Forest Sector Strategy Paper - April 23, 2002, 2001-07-13 - 2002-04-22; 01832579
  - Conferences and Seminars - Africa Day - United Nations - Conference File, 2002-04-03; 01832592
  - Conferences and Seminars - African Workshop on the World Summit on Sustainable Development - Preparation Meeting - April 23, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-04-23; 01832512
  - Conferences and Seminars - Agricultural Science and Technology Roundtable Discussions with the Private Sector - December 5, 2000 - General Correspondence, 2000-11-28; 01832575
  - Conferences and Seminars - Annual Environment Forum - Annapolis - March 20 - 22, 2000 - Correspondence File, 2000-01-20 - 2000-03-17; 01832420
  - Conferences and Seminars - Asia - Pacific Roundtable - Georgetown University - November 28 - 29, 2000 - Conference File, 2000-11-29; 01832424
  - Conferences and Seminars - Bellagio Forum for Sustainable Development Annual Meeting - December 12 - 14, 2001 - Correspondence File, 2001-12-05 - 2001-12-14; 01832412
  - Conferences and Seminars - Cotton and Global Trade Negotiations Conference - The World Bank - July 8 - 9, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-06-12 - 2002-07-08; 01832586
  - Conferences and Seminars - Agricultural Science and Technology Roundtable Discussion - April 16, 2001 - General Correspondence, 2001-04-04 - 2001-04-16; 01832573
  - Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Day at the United Nations - New York - September 30, 1998 - General Correspondence, 1998-05-15 - 1998-09-25; 01832591
  - Conferences and Seminars - Empowerment Retreat - May 7 - 8, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-05-07 - 2002-05-08; 01832584
  - Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Week and Sustainable Development Month - April 2002 - General Correspondence, 2002-04-01 - 2002-04-21; 01832577
  - Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Week - March 10 - 14, 2003 - General Correspondence, 2003-02-21 - 2003-03-11; 01832572
  - Conferences and Seminars - ESSD European Forum - Paris - May 29 - 30, 2001 - Correspondence File, 2001-05-08 - 2001-05-30; 01832410
  - Conferences and Seminars - Finance, Mining and Sustainability Conference - April 8-9, 2001 - Correspondence File, 2000-11-01 - 2001-04-09; 01832408
  - Conferences and Seminars - First Meeting of a Global Consultative Process on an International Assessment of the Role of Agricultural Science and Technology in Reducing Hunger, Improving Rural Livelihoods, and Stimulating Economic Growth - Conference File, 2002-11-06 - 2002-11-08; 01832503
  - Conferences and Seminars - ESSD Vice Presidential Day at the UN - April 18, 2001 - Briefing Book, 2001-04-12 - 2001-04-18; 01832409
  - Conferences and Seminars - Freshwater Conference - Bonn - December 3 - 7, 2001 - Conference Papers, 2001-11-14 - 2001-12-07; 01832414
  - Conferences and Seminars - GEF Ministerial Roundtable on Financing Environment and Sustainable Development - Monterrey, Mexico - March 17 - 18, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-03-17 - 2002-03-18; 01832567
  - Conferences and Seminars - Global Accords for Sustainable Development: Innovative Mechanisms and Enabling Technologies - Cambridge, MA - September 16 - 17, 1998 - Correspondence File, 1998-09-16 - 1998-09-17; 01832505
  - Conferences and Seminars - Globe 2002 Seventh Biennial Trade Fair and Conference on Business and the Environment - Vancouver - March 13 - 15, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-03-13 - 2002-03-15; 01832566
  - Conferences and Seminars - Food Security: A Pillar of Sustainable Development - Delhi Sustainable Development - February 8 - 11, 2001 - Conference File - Speech by Ian Johnson, 2001-02-08 - 2001-02-11; 01832501
  - Conferences and Seminars - Hydropower in the Implementation Plan of WSSD - Exchange Between Brazil and the International Rivers Network - November 16 - 18, 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-11-16 - 2002-11-18; 01832514
  - Conferences and Seminars - Interagency Standing Committee - 23rd. Meeting - UNICEF House - December 6, 1999, 1999-12-06; 01832416
  - Conferences and Seminars - International Landcare Conference - Melbourne - March 2 - 5, 2000 - Correspondence File, 2000-02-28 - 2000-03-13; 01832422
  - Conferences and Seminars - International Funders for Indigenous Peoples - July 10, 2002 - General Correspondence, 2002-05-17 - 2002-07-10; 01832585
  - Conferences and Seminars - IUCN Council Task Force on Governance - August - October, 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-08-01 - 2002-10-31; 01832519
  - Conferences and Seminars - Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development [OECD] Roundtable on Sustainable Development - Paris - December 6, 2001 - General Correspondence, 2001-10-12 - 2001-12-06; 01832583
  - Conferences and Seminars - Preparatory Meeting of the WSSD: Passing of the Torch From Rio de Janeiro to Johnnesberg - Rio de Janeiro - June 23 - 25, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-06-23 - 2002-06-25; 01832444
  - Conferences and Seminars - Preparatory Meetings for WSSD Johannesburg, Briefing on Development at UN Forum on Forests (UNFF) - Presentation at New School University - New York - November 20, 2001 - Conference File, 2001-11-20; 01832449
  - Conferences and Seminars - Public Health and Sustainable Development - School of Advanced International Studies - Johns Hopkins University - November 13, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-11-13; 01832509
  - Conferences and Seminars - Rural Strategy Update Retreat - July 17, 2000 - Conference File, 2000-07-17; 01832587
  - Conferences and Seminars - Keidanren Nature Conservation Fund - Symposium on Nature Conservation in Asia - September 2, 1998 - General Correspondence, 1998-08-07 - 1998-09-02; 01832589
  - Conferences and Seminars - Soliciting Chinese Participation in Post WSSD Intenational Assessment of Agricultural Science and Technology - Memorandum and Briefing Material from Ian Johnsonto to Executive Director Guangyao Zhu - Correspondence File, 2003-01-31; 01832516
  - Conferences and Seminars - Rural Week 2001 - General Correspondence, 2001-04-18 - 2001-04-23; 01832569
  - Conferences and Seminars - The Berlin Forum - Committed to Sustainability - Berlin - May 20 - 23, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-05-03 - 2002-05-09; 01832593
  - Conferences and Seminars - The Global Environment - Presentation by Ian Johnson - New York - November 20, 2001 - Conference File, 2001-11-20; 01832518
  - Conferences and Seminars - Third Training Course on Environmental Economics and Policy - Shenzhen, China - October 12 - 22, 1999 - Training File, 1999-07-29 - 1999-10-19; 01832421
  - Conferences and Seminars - United Nations [UN] Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) - Buenos Aires - November 1 - 12, 1998 - General Correspondence, 1998-10-21 - 1998-11-04; 01832590
  - Conferences and Seminars - Voices and Choices at a Macro Level - Participation in Country - Owned Poverty Reduction Strategies - Washington, D.C. - April 3 - 5, 2001 - Conference File, 2001-04-03 - 2001-04-05; 01832502
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Prepcom III - April 3 - 4, 2002 - Conference File, 2002-04-03 - 2002-04-04; 01832441
  - Conferences and Seminars - World Water Forum - December 2, 2002 - Correspondence File, 2002-11-15 - 2002-12-03; 01832417
- Policy and guidelines development and supporting materials, 1994 - 2003 (predominant 1998 - 2003); WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-08; 6.05 linear feet of textual records
  Series consists of records related to ESSD and Bank-wide policy and guidelines development. In some cases, ESSDVP and Vice President Ian Johnson played active roles in the development of policy and guidelines while in others reports and correspondence were forwarded to ESSDVP for comment or for informational purposes. The series contains some records that evidence the formation of institutional rules and policies, namely Operational Policy and Business Practice (OP/BP). However, the majority of records in this series are the product of ESSDVP research and information exchange on various topics for the purpose of writing reports, planning projects, or developing relationships with external agencies, institutions, and governments.
  The series contains a significant amount of records related to the development and evaluation of OP/BP. Records related to Bank forestry policy are numerous and include: a copy of Forest Policy Implementation Review and Strategy (OP/BP 4.36); a copy of Revised Forestry Strategy for the World Bank Group; minutes of an ad hoc group on the topic; ESSD Council meeting minutes on the topic; related correspondence; and an inventory of projects having to do with the topic. Series also contains records related to OP 4.12 Involuntary Resettlement and OP/BP 13.05 Guidelines for Projects Supervision. These include: correspondence; drafts of policy; and comments made by ESSDVP staff.
  Records of the Operational Policy Committee Meeting from 1999 to 2002 are also included; records discuss OP/BP and guideline development. Records include: minutes; agendas; reports; comments; correspondence; and supporting materials.
  Records in this series that do not relate to the development of specific policy may relate to ESSDVP and Ian Johnson's involvement in the research and writing of guidelines, reports, and evaluations but may also be limited to providing comments or receiving reports and correspondence for informational purposes. Topics include but are not limited to: human rights; indigenous peoples; safeguard policies; social development strategic directions; civil society; disaster management; water management and infrastructure; food assessment; climate change; desertification and drylands management; fisheries; commodity price risk management; global public policy; investment in energy infrastructure; promoting sustainability in development; and Green procurement. Records on these topics include but are not limited to: final and draft versions of reports; comments from ESSDVP and, most often, Vice President Johnson; correspondence; meeting agendas and minutes; and briefing notes. Records from meetings and workshops attended and, in some cases, participated in by Johnson are included. These records include event and background materials and Johnson's notes.
  A small amount of files contain records forwarded to Johnson from the Social Development Department (SDV) of ESSD. Topics of these records include: NGO/Bank relations; community driven development; cultural development; civil society; and post conflict development. Records generally include reports and correspondence.
  Records related to Johnson's activities involving the Global Environment Facility (GEF) are also included, although small in number. These include correspondence and informational reports forwarded to Johnson and materials from replenishment meetings attended by Johnson.
  The series also contains final reports and other records that the Operations Evaluation Department (OED, now the Independent Evaluation Group [IEG]) created that relate either directly to ESSD or to topics relevant to ESSD's sectors. OED reports found in this series include: OED Review of the Bank's Performance on the Environment (2001, draft, accompanied by presentation slides); Phase I Interim Report: 'Promoting Environmental Sustainability in Development: An Evaluation of the World Bank's Performance' (2000); Safeguard Policy Framework: OED Comments on Systemic Issues (2000); OED Forest Strategy Review (2000); OED Review of the World Bank Forest Strategy and Its Implementation (2000); The World Bank and Global Public Policies and Programs: An Evaluation Strategy (2001); How Far into the Mainstream? A Review of Environmental Issues in IDA Activities (2001); IDA's Partnership for Poverty Reduction (FY94-FY00) (2001); and OED IDA Review: Environmental Sustainability Issues in IDA 10-12 (2000). A number of reports on Forest Development and World Bank Assistance related to specific countries (China, India, and Brazil) are also included and are accompanied by briefing materials. Records that accompany reports include comments from ESSDVP and sector department staff as well as correspondence. A small amount of correspondence and reports forwarded to ESSDVP for informational purposes that relate to the Committee on Development Effectiveness (CODE) are also included in this series.
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01831147
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01831148
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File, 2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01831149
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File, 1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31; 01831146
  - Policy Development Records - Human Rights - Correspondence - February 27, 2003, 2003-02-26; 01831240
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Revised Forest Strategy for the World Bank Group - Board Meeting and Management Response - October 29 - 31, 2002, 2002-10-29 - 2002-10-31; 01831238
  - Policy Development Records - Human Rights and the World Bank - Correspondence - September - November 2002, 2002-06-17 - 2002-11-10; 01831241
  - Indigenous Peoples Meeting - Correspondence - October 17, 2002, 2002-10-03 - 2002-10-16; 01831278
  - Indigenous Peoples Meeting - Correspondence - October 2, 2002, 2002-08-07 - 2002-10-02; 01831279
  - Policy Development Records - Proposed Memorandum of Understanding with International Organization for Migration - Correspondence - November 8, 2001, 2001-10-09 - 2001-11-08; 01831281
  - Policy Development Records - Safeguard Policies - Framework for Improving Development Effectiveness - Correspondence - August 13, 2002, 2002-08-13; 01831280
  - Policy Development Records - Strategic Directions for the World Bank in Social Development - Correspondence - October 15 - 16, 2002, 2002-10-10 - 2002-10-14; 01831283
  - Empowerment, Culture and Civic Engagement - Proposed R and D Program - Follow-Up on External Advisory Committee Meeting - November 5, 2001, 2001-11-02 - 2001-11-05; 01831282
  - Policy Development Records - World Bank Engagement with Civil Society - Report - October 3, 2001, 2001-09-24 - 2001-10-03; 01831376
  - Policy Development Records - Water Resources Management - Correspondence - 1998 - 2001, 1998-12-01 - 2001-07-22; 01831627
  - Policy Development Records - Disaster Management - Prevention Consortium and World Institute for Natural Disasters - March 1999 and February 2000 - Correspondence, 1998-07-06 - 2000-01-31; 01831626
  - Policy Development Records - Use of World Bank Funds for Land Acquisition - Correspondence - December 2000 - October 2001, 2000-12-22 - 2001-10-16; 01831628
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - NGO Unit and Bank - NGO Relations - Correspondence File, 1999-11-01 - 2001-05-31; 01831706
  - Policy Development Records - World Bank - Global Environment Facility [GEF] Quarterly Management Meeting - Correspondence - April 2, 2002, 2002-02-08 - 2002-04-02; 01831629
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - Foundations and Community Driven Development - Correspondence File, 1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01831708
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Involuntary Resettlement - Committee on Development Effectiveness - Correspondence File - 1999, 1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31; 01831713
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - Cultural Development 2000 - Correspondence File, 2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01831709
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - NGOs and Steering Committee on NGOs - Correspondence File - 1999 - 2000, 1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31; 01831714
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environment - Climate Change - Correspondence File, 1998-07-08 - 2001-06-14; 01832149
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environment - Global Environment Facility (GEF) - Correspondence File, 1998-05-20 - 1999-12-21; 01832152
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD - SDV General - Correspondence File - 2000 - 2001, 2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31; 01831716
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD / RDV - General - Correspondence File, 1998-12-01 - 2000-11-16; 01832162
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - RDV - Forestry - Correspondence File, 1999-09-24 - 2001-03-29; 01832169
  - Policy Development Records - Desertification and Drylands Management - Correspondence - 1998 - 2000, 1998-08-06 - 2000-12-06; 01832170
  - Policy Development Records - Fisheries - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001, 1999-03-19 - 2001-07-11; 01832171
  - Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD - Environment General - Correspondence File, 2000-05-03 - 2000-09-25; 01832157
  - Policy Development Records - Commodities Price Risk Management - Correspondence - 2000 - 2001, 2000-12-14 - 2001-06-01; 01832175
  - Policy Development Records - Water Resources Management and Land Management - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001, 1999-08-25 - 2001-03-20; 01832174